Walter B. Cannon Papers 1905-1928 Mss.B.C163.1
American Philosophical Society
If one generality applies to the antivivisectionists, it was that they were predominately female. White, renowned as founder of the AAVS, and a brilliant lecturer, was perhaps the most prominent, but women were the backbone of the movement at the grassroots level as both leaders and participants. Women such as Mary F. Lovell and Diana Belais organized antivivisection societies, provided funding, wrote articles and edited the magazine Zoophilly, sought support from women's organizations, and lectured widely. The movement's leaders were generally drawn from families of good social standing, and many were active in other social reform movements (e.g. temperance movement).
Women shaped the movement from its ideological underpinnings to its rhetoric, strategy, and tactics. They stressed emotional elements such as compassion, affection, and caring for the young and defenseless, traits commonly regarded at the time as distinctly "feminine" and "maternal". They considered themselves responsible for setting children on the correct moral path, which included steering them away from cruelty to animals, and they took advantage of their association with women's groups to spread their antivivisection message.
The principal objection to animal experimentation among antivivisectionists was a moral and ethical one. They argued that it is fundamentally immoral to sacrifice sentient creatures to gain scientific knowledge, but more subtly, that claimed that vivisection decreased the moral sensibility of physicians, and by impairing their sense of compassion, would jeopardize public safety. Whether in the laboratory or slaughterhouse, they contended that cruelty to animals corrupted morality. Their ethical concern therefore extended to and included human subjects, especially orphans and hospital patients. Arguing that it was their particular duty to protect the young from exposure to the cruelty inherent in animal experimentation, they succeeded in securing legislation to prohibit vivisection in elementary and secondary schools.
Of all the proposals to regulate vivisection in the last decades of the 19th century and first quarter of the 20th century, the bils presented to Congress in 1896 and 1900 respectively presented the greatest challenge to the medical community. Representative James McMillan of Michigan introduced a bill in 1896 to regulate vivisection in the District of Columbia, modelled on the British act of 1876. After a public hearing, however, the vote was postponed due to the Spanish American War. A similar proposal was put forward in 1900 by Senator Jacob Gallinger from New Hampshire, who had conducted the Senate hearings in 1896. Antivivisectionists had hoped that by securing restriction at the federal level, it would be easier to bring about changes in local laws. Despite support from the public, academics, religious leaders, Supreme Court justices, and even a number of physicians, however, the bill languished due to intensive last minute political lobbying by Welch and other physicians.
The Gallinger bill served as a wake up call for the medical establishment. Even though the bill was defeated, the experience was sobering. Quick to learn their lesson, physicians realized the need to redouble their efforts to defend animal research, making full use of their political connections to push their agenda. Provivisection activists were quick to urge the Council for the Defence of Medical Research to be aggressive in the political sphere, as wellas they public sphere, and they closed ranks around their common cause. Even though Welch and Keen did not agree on everything, leading defenders of animal research always made sure to keep their disputes private and their community in excellent order.
Ultimately, the decline of the antivivisection movement can be traced to several causes beyond the effective response of the medical community. For quite some time it has been maintained that the discovery of diphtheria antitoxin and other major medical developments brought the antivivisectionists to their knees, and that the outbreak of war in 1914 altered moral priorities. Soldiers had to be vaccinated against typhoid and urgent questions about illnesses affecting the troops tempted medical researchers to turn increasingly to laboratory animals for answers. Antivivisection advocates uniformly opposed these activities, and as a result lost support among the general public. More generally, antivivisectionists were not helped by their tendency to misrepresentation and exaggeration, and their use of inaccurate, vague and outdated references. Although antivivisectionists continued to press for legislative changes into the 1920s, they were so thoroughly unsucessful that the many members of the medical community felt confident in declaring victory. Where Cannon had contributed twelve pieces against antivivisection between 1921 and 1926, he wrote only a single article on the subject in the 1930s.
American Medical Association.; Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837; League of Nations.; Lister, Joseph, Baron, 1827-1912; Mitchell, S. Weir, (Silas Weir), 1829-1914; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; University of Minnesota.; University of Pennsylvania.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Evolution; Medicine-United States; Neurology-United States; Science and Technology; Scientific Correspondence; Shock.; Surgery-United States; Tuberculosis; Typhoid vaccine; Vivisection
- Walter B. Cannon Papers, 1905-1928 (Box 1-6)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1905 May 1; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1905 May 3; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1908 December 4; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1908 December 8; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1908 December 9; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 March 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 March 11; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 April 13; 2p.; Paget, Stephen (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 June 22; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 July 6; 2p.; Dix, E. C. (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 July 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 July 13; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 September 22; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 September 28; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 October 4; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 October 16; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 October 18; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 October 18; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 October 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 October 29; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 October 30; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 November 1; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 November 9; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 November 11; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 November 12; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 November 13; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to the editor of Zoophily, 1909 November 13; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 November 18; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 November 19; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 December 10; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 December 13; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 December 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 December 21; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 December 22; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1909 December 23; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1909 December 30; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 3; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 January 4; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 7; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 7; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Not found: 2/18/2011
    General note
    Unlocated 3/11
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 January 10; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 January 17; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 22; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 January 24; 3p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 27; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 January 28; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 January 31; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 February 11; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Feb 14; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Feb 19; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Feb 21; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Feb 24; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Feb 26; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Feb 28; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Mar 1; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 7; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Mar 8; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 11; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Mar 12; 2 copies, 4p. each; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 14; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 16; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 18; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Charles E. Hughes, 1910 Mar 18; 2 copies, 3p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
    Includes Cannon to Charles E. Huighes, March 19, 1910, 2 copies, 6p. each
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 21; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Mar 28; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Mar 29; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Apr 1; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Apr 4; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Apr 5; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Apr 6; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Apr 6; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Apr 7; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Apr 7; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Apr 15; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Apr 19; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 Apr 25; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 May 6; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 May 13; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 May 16; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 June 13; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 June 19; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 June 23; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 June 28; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 June 29; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1910 June 30; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Nov 3; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Nov 5; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Nov 26; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Nov 28; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1910 Dec 29; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Jan 14; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 Feb 16; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 Feb 20; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 Feb 23; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 May 30; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 June 12; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 June 26; 3p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 June 28; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 July 13; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 July 17; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 July 18; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 July 21; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Sep 11; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Oct 18; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Oct 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 Oct 23; 5p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Oct 27; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to William W. Keen, 1911 Oct 31; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Nov 13; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1911 Nov 22; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 1)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Mar 7; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1912 Mar 8; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Mar 22; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1912 Mar 23; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Apr 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Aug 29; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Aug 29; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Sep 5; 3p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Sep 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Sep 13; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Sep 13; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Sep 30; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Oct 12; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Oct 18; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Oct 22; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1912 Oct 23; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Nov 12; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Nov 21; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1912 Nov 22; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Nov 25; 1p.; Simmons, G. H. (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1912 Nov 27; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Nov 30; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1912 Dec 24; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1913 Jan 5; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Jan 7; 2p.; Pearce, R. M. (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1913 Jan 22; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Jan 25; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to R. G. [i.e. R. M.] Pearce, 1913 Nov 8; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to R. M. Pearce, 1913 Nov 8; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1913 Nov 26; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to R. M. Pearce, 1913 Dec 12; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to R. M. Pearce, 1913 Dec 15; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Dec 16; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Stephen Paget, 1913 Dec 17; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1913 Dec 18; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Dec 18; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Dec 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Dec 23; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to R. M. Pearce, 1913 Dec 26; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1913 Dec 31; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Jan 1; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to R. M. Pearce, 1914 Jan 1; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Jan 3; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 3; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Jan 3; 1p.; Cabot, R. C. (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 7; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 10; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Jan 12; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 12; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
    Includes newsclipping on vivisection; copies of letters from John Richardson to Joseph B. Cummins, September 25, 1913 (3p.) and William R. Bradshaw to Cummins, Oct. 19, 1913; and B. F. McGrath, "The 'Open door,' Mr. Bradshaw, and the Mayo Clinic," January 9, 1914.
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Jan 13; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Jan 29; 2p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 2; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 4; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Feb 7; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 9; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Feb 10; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 11; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 11; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 20; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Feb 26; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914; 1p.; Belais, Diana (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 27; 2p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Feb 27; 2p.; Lee, Frederick S. (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Mar 2; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Mar 5; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Mar 17; 3p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Mar 18; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Mar 19; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Mar 23; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Mar 25; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)
  - to Walter B. Cannon, 1914 Mar 27; 1p.; Keen, William W., (William Williams), b. 1837 (Box 2)
  - to William W. Keen, 1914 Apr 1; 1p.; Cannon, Walter B., (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945 (Box 2)